Your media player does not support the subtitle format used in this episode. Subtitles will likely not function properly. Please use one of the recommended video players, preferably mpv: https://mpv.io
.مشغل الفيديو الخاص بك لا يدعم صيغة ملف الترجمة المستخدمة في هذه الحلقة .من المحتمل ألا تعمل الترجمة بشكل صحيح يرجى استخدام أحد مشغلات الفيديو :على سبيل المثال mpv الموصى بها، كمشغل https://mpv.io
Navy Headquarters New World
مقر البحرية بالعالم الجديد
You must be happy, Issho...
،لا بدّ أنك سعيدٌ يا إيشو
{The abolition of the Seven Warlords of the Sea was what you all really wanted...-OG}Abolishing the Seven Warlords was what you all wanted.
.فقد كانت غايتك إلغاء نظام الشّيتشيبوكاي
{I was against it, but the leaders' decision can't be reversed.-OG}I was against it, but we must abide by the sovereigns' decision.
.لا بد من التقيد بقرار القادة رغم معارضتي له
Dammit! How can they all be so naive?!
!سُحقًا، ما مدى سذاجة الجميع؟
Justice comes with a price–
...للعدالة ثمن دائمًا
And there's no other way?
ولا مهرب منها؟
You can't understand because you've never been one of them...
...لن تفهم لأنّك لم تكن يومًا واحدًا منهم
{The world where innocent weak people get ignored is worthless!-OG}A world where the weak and innocent are disregarded is worthless!
!لا قيمة لعالم يُهمَل فيه الضعاف الأبرياء
Hurry up! Keep moving!
!بسرعة! واصلوا التّقدّم
Hurry!
!أسرعوا
The Seven Warlords of the Sea are no more.
.لم يعد للشيتشيبوكاي أي أثر
{Let's believe in the SSG, the Navy's Special Science Group.-OG}Let's have faith in the SSG, the Navy's Special Science Group.
لنضع ثقتنا في مجموعة البحريّة .«العلميّة الخاصّة «ب ع خ
{The balance of power in the world is about to change drastically!-OG}The world's balance of power is about to shift drastically!
،توازن القوى في العالم على مشارف تغيير جذريّ
But we don't know how it'll change!
!لكننا نجهل مسار ذلك التّغيير
{I heard that Kaido and Big Mom will team up in Wano...-OG}Word is that Kaido and Big Mom are forming an alliance in Wano!
...سمعتُ أنّ كايدو وبيغ مام قد تحالفا في بلاد وانو
What?!
!ماذا؟
Issho
إيشو
Could it mean the return of the Rocks?!
!ألا يعني هذا عودة الروكس؟
Don't speak of it like it's just some legend!
!لا تتحدّث عنهم وكأنّهم أسطورة أو ما شابه
It's all true...
...كل ما يُشاع عنهم حقيقي
{and a disaster that menaces us despite how busy we are at the moment!-OG}and it's a disaster that menaces us despite how preoccupied we are!
!وهو كارثة تهدّدنا رغم انشغالنا البالغ حاليًّا
{What?! Two Emperors of the Sea joined forces?!-OG}What?! Two Emperors joined forces?!
!ماذا؟! تحالَف اثنان من اليونكو؟
No way!
!مُحال
Now of all times?!
!وفي وقت كهذا؟
{To be precise, we got information that they'll team up in the days ahead...-OG}More accurately, intelligence indicates they'll team up in the coming days.
بشكل أدقّ، وصلتنا معلومات أنّ ...تحالفهما مزمع في الأيّام القادمة
{They haven't done any harm so far and we don't know their purpose or how to deal with it yet.-OG}They haven't done any harm so far and we don't know their objective or how to deal with it yet.
،لم يتسبّبا في أيّ أضرار حتّى الآن .ونجهل هدفهما وكيفية مواجهتهما
The only thing that connects those two is...
...الشّيء الوحيد المشترك بينهما
the legendary Rocks Pirates.
.هو قراصنة الروكس الأسطوريّون
But there isn't much information about them, either...
...لكن لا توجد معلومات كافية عنهم أيضًا
Big Mom and Kaido have hated each other for a long time...
...كرَهَ كلّ من بيغ مام وكايدو بعضهما لوقتٍ طويل
I never expected such a thing would ever happen.
.لم أتوقّع حدوث أمر كهذا
Sengoku, who are the Rocks Pirates?
من هم الروكس يا سينغوكو-سان؟
Oh, yeah.
،صحيح
You are too young to know about them...
...أنتم شباب ولا علم لكم بهم
{The Rocks Pirates were a gang of unique characters who gathered together...-OG}The Rocks Pirates was a crew of personalities who gathered together...
كان قراصنة الروكس مجموعةٌ فريدة ...من الأشخاص اجتمعوا معًا
{around just one money-making scheme on the Pirate Island of Hachinosu ages ago.-OG}for a money-making scheme on Pirate Island, Hachinosu, ages ago.
لخطّة مدرّة للأموال في جزيرة .القراصنة هاتشينوسو منذ زمن طويل
{They were all so violent, they even battled to the death on board their own ship.-OG}They were all so violent, they would even battle to the death on board their own ship.
كانوا عنيفين للغاية لدرجة أنّهم تقاتلوا .حتّى الموت حتّى على متن سفينتهم
Its members were, first, Captain Rocks...
...وكان يتألّف أعضاؤها من القبطان روكس
A young Whitebeard!
!واللّحية البيضاء في عزّ شبابه
Big Mom!
!وبيغ مام
And Kaido!
!وكايدو
Really?
...هذا أمرٌ لا يعقل
{Those three used to be on board the same pirate ship.-OG}Those three used to serve aboard the same pirate ship.
كان هؤلاء الثّلاثة يبحرون .على متن نفس سفينة القراصنة
– What?!
!ماذا؟
N-No way!
!مـ-مستحيل
I-I can't believe it!
!لا-لا أصدّق هذا
{There are other pirates from the Rocks Pirates, who later became infamous.-OG}Others from the Rocks Pirates became infamous as well.
ثمّة قراصنة آخرون من صفوف .طاقم الروكس ذاع صيتهم لاحقًا أيضًا
{Shiki the Golden Lion who used to be a big name and even vied for supremacy in the New World.-OG}Shiki the Golden Lion, a big name who vied for dominance in the New World.
كالأسد الذّهبيّ شيكي الّذي كان مشهورًا .وتنافس على سيادة العالم الجديد
{There were still others like Silver Axe, Captain John, and Wang Zhi...-OG}There were also others like Silver Axe, Captain John, and Wang Zhi...
وآخرون أيضًا مثل الفأس الفضّيّة ...والقبطان جون وأوتشوكو
You've got to be kidding!
!لا بدّ أنّك تمزح! كلها أسماء قراصنة كبار
How was such a pirate group lost to history?
لماذا نسيَ التّاريخ مجموعة قراصنة كهؤلاء؟
{One of the reasons is that they disliked each other so much,-OG}Firstly, they hated each other so much that they took no pride in publicizing their exploits.
،أحد الأسباب هو كرههم الشّديد لبعضهم .كما لم يتفاخروا علنًا بإنجازاتهم
Secondly...
...إضافةً لذلك
{Captain Rocks had the ambition to become the king of the world...-OG}Captain Rocks wanted to become the king of the world.
...فقد طمح القبطان روكس ليصبح ملك العالم
{So they showed their teeth at the World Government as if they were a terrorist group,-OG}They began a campaign of savage provocation against the World Government.
لذلك كشّروا عن أنيابهم لحكومة .العالم وكأنّهم مجموعة إرهابيّة
{and the government has been covering up incidents since.-OG}Their terrorist acts too violent to suppress,
وكانت أعمالهم الإرهابية ،أعنف مما يمكن التستر عليه
{But everyone knew how threatening they were at that time...-OG}the world came to fear their very name.
لكنّ الجميع كانوا يعلمون .مدى خطرهم في ذلك الوقت
A particularly fateful incident took place at God Valley thirty-eight years ago.
وقعت حادثة مصيريّة معيّنة .في ڠود ڤالي قبل 38 عامًا
38 Years Ago
قبل 38 عامًا
{It was reported on the news that the world's strongest Rocks Pirates...-OG}The news reported that the Rocks Pirates, known as the world's strongest pirate crew...
أفادت الأخبار أنّ قراصنة الروكس الأقوى
were annihilated on that island.
...في العالم قد أُبيدوا في تلك الجزيرة
{No one could stop the advancement of the evil,-OG}That unstoppable force of evil was defeated...
،لم يقوَ أحد على وضع حدّ لتقدّم الشّرّ
{but Navy Headquarters' Vice Admiral Garp was able to!-OG}by Navy Headquarters' Vice Admiral Garp!
!إلاّ نائب الأميرال في البحريّة غارب
His name became known throughout the world
انتشر اسمه كالنار في الهشيم حول العالم
{and people started calling him the hero of the Navy.-OG}and people began calling him the Hero of the Navy.
.وبدأ النّاس يلقبونه ببطل البحريّة
{So that's the beginning of Vice Admiral Garp's many tales of heroism!-OG}So that's how Vice Admiral Garp began his many acts of heroism!
إذًا فتلك بداية قصص بطولة !نائب الأميرال غارب العديدة
{There are countless tales of heroism involving Vice Admiral Garp,-OG}There are countless tales of valor involving Vice Admiral Garp,
ثمّة الكثير من القصص البطولية ،الّتي تشمل نائب الأميرال غارب
but I didn't know there was yet another great episode like that!
!لكنّني لم أعلم أنّ هنالك فصلًا عظيمًا آخر منها
He's really something!
!إنّه مميّز فعلًا
Big Mom and Kaido?!
!بيغ مام وكايدو؟
Enough already...
...هذا يكفي
But he generally refuses to discuss it.
.لكنّه يرفض الحديث عن ذلك أحيانًا
What? Why?
لماذا؟
I'll fill you in so you can learn some history...
...سأطلعكم على الأمر لتكونوا ملمّين ببعض التّاريخ
{One of the reasons he doesn't share was never reported in the papers.-OG}One reason was kept out of the newspapers,
...السبب الأول: لم يُذكر الأمر في أيٍّ من الصحف
{It was necessary to work alongside a pirate to fight that battle.-OG}but Garp had no choice but to join forces with a pirate in that fight.
ولكن في تلك المعركة حُتم عليه .أن يتعاون مع أحد القراصنة
A pirate?!
!مع قرصانٍ؟
{The other reason is he happened to save the Celestial Dragons.-OG}He also happened to save some Celestial Dragons.
.والسّبب الآخر هو أنّه أنقذ التّنانين السّماويّة
The Celestial Dragons were part of that story?!
التّنانين السّماويّة كانوا جزءًا من القصّة؟
{Well, it's a marine's duty to protect the Celestial Dragons.-OG}Well, it is a marine's duty to protect Celestial Dragons.
في الواقع، حماية التنانين السماوية .أحد واجبات جندي البحرية
What's the issue here?
!ما الخطب في ذلك؟
{Garp's moral compass tells him that it's not his duty.-OG}Garp is morally opposed to fulfilling that duty.
.كان غارب يعارض هذا الواجب أخلاقيًّا
{One of the reasons that Garp refuses to become the admiral is...-OG}One of the reasons Garp refuses to become an admiral...
أحد الأسباب الّتي تدفع غارب ...لرفض منصب الأميرال
{because admirals are the Celestial Dragons' direct subordinates.-OG}is that they are the direct subordinates of the Celestial Dragons.
.هو أنّ الأميرالات أعوان مباشرون للتّنانين السّماويّة
Despite openly showing contempt for them,
إنّه يُظهر علنًا عدم الاحترام لهم، ولكن .يُفصَح عنه بفضل إنجازاته وشعبيّته
Now, the truth of the matter is...
...الحقيقة خلف هذه المسألة
to protect the Celestial Dragons and their slaves at God Valley,
من أجل حماية التّنانين السّماويّة ،وعبيدهم في ڠود ڤالي
Garp and Roger, who happened to be there,
فقد تعاون غارب مع روجر الّذي !كان هناك لهزيمة قراصنة الروكس
It's known as the God Valley Incident!
!وهذا ما يُعرف بحادثة ڠود ڤالي
Retired
متقاعد
He teamed up with...
...لقد تعاون مع ملك القراصنة
...the Pirate King...
...جنبًا لجنب
...to fight?!
!وقاتلا معًا؟
The Celestial Dragons, Roger, and Rocks?!
!التّنانين السّماويّة وروجر وروكس؟
{I can't believe they were all at the same place at the same time!-OG}They were all there at the same time?!
!لا أصدّق أنّهم كانوا جميعًا في نفس المكان والوقت !ماذا حدث تحديدًا في تلك الجزيرة؟
I've never even heard of God Valley!
!«لم أسمع مُسبقًا عن «ڠود ڤالي
It's no wonder.
...لا عجب في ذلك
The place called God Valley...
«بقعة الأرض المعروفة بـ«ڠود ڤالي
is nowhere to be found on any map now.
.لم تعد موجودةً في أي خريطة حديثة
In fact, it disappeared without a trace.
...في الحقيقة، اختفت الجزيرة بلا أثر
The island that the World Government wanted to hide disappeared...
...الجزيرة الّتي أرادت حكومة العالم إخفاءها قد اختفت
Do you still want to hear about it?
أما زلتم تريدون معرفة المزيد عن الجزيرة؟
{Once, the ambitious Rocks tried to become the king of the world,-OG}Rocks was so zealous in his goal to become king of the world
،ذات مرّة، حاول روكس الطّموح أن يصبح ملك العالم
that he broke one too many taboos,
،لكنّه انتهك العديد من المحرّمات ...لذلك ما عادت المعلومات متوفّرة عنه
{He is only remembered by some Navy soldiers of our generation.-OG}He is remembered only by a handful of Navy marines from my generation.
.لا يتذكّره إلاّ القليل من جنود البحريّة من جيلنا
{Even it was a long time ago, I can't believe there was a man who led three pirates-OG}Even if it was a long time ago, I can't imagine one man leading three future emperors!
حتّى إن كان ذلك منذ زمن، فلا أصدق وجود !ثلاثة قراصنة أصبحوا يُنعتون باليونكو لاحقًا
{For Roger, maybe Rocks was his first and strongest enemy...-OG}Rocks might have been Roger's first, and strongest, foe.
...أمّا روجر، ربّما كان روكس هو أوّل وأقوى عدوّ له
Strangely enough, Roger and Rocks had something in common.
والغريب في الأمر، كان ثمّة أمر .مشترك بين روجر وروكس
Rocks' full name was Rocks D. Xebec.
.اسم روكس الكامل هو روكس دي زيبيك
He’s already passed on,
،مع أنّه كان قد مات سلفًا
{he was one of those pirates who have the name "D."!-OG}but he was among those pirates who bear the name “D.”!
إلّا أنه كان أحد القراصنة .«ممّن يحملون اسم «دي
Retired
متقاعد
It's true that Kaido and Big Mom were on board the same ship...
صحيح أنّ كايدو وبيغ مام كانا ...على متن نفس السّفينة
Retired
متقاعد
But their capabilities are totally different from thirty-eight years ago.
لكنّ قدراتهما مختلفة بالكامل .عمّا كانت عليه قبل 38 سنة
{If they really team up, we're about to see the world's worst pirate group.-OG}If this alliance is true, we're about to see the world's most dangerous group of pirates.
إن كانا قد تحالفا فعلًا، فنحن على وشك .رؤية أخطر مجموعة قراصنة في العالم
Brannew! How much are their bounties now?
برانيو! كم بلغت قيمة مكافآتهم الآن؟
Ah, yes.
صحيح، علينا الإعلان عن مكافآت جديدة لأولئك .الّذين جُرّدوا من لقب الشّيتشيبوكاي أيضًا
Let's review all of their numbers.
.لنراجع كلّ مكافآتهم
Starting with Blackbeard,
،بدءًا من اللحية السوداء
{who started to be called an Emperor of the Sea about a year ago...-OG}who started to be called an Emperor about a year ago...
...الذي أصبح يونكو قبل عامٍ مضى
{He recruited some powerful subordinates when he raided Impel Down two years ago,-OG}He recruited powerful subordinates during the raid on Impel Down two years ago,
لقد جنّد بعض الأعوان الأقوياء ،عندما أغار على إمبل داون قبل عامين
{and now has gained control over the Pirate Island of Hachinosu.-OG}and now has gained control over Pirate Island, Hachinosu.
كما أحكم سيطرته الآن على .جزيرة القراصنة هاتشينوسو
{He's still extending his influence taking Whitebeard's place!-OG}He's still extending his influence, filling Whitebeard's void!
!ما زال يواصل فرض سيطرته آخذًا مكان اللّحية البيضاء
The commodore of the Blackbeard Pirates,
،عميد قراصنة اللحية السوداء
Marshall D. Teach!
!مارشال دي تيتش
2,247,600,000 belly!
!ملياران و247 مليونًا و600 ألف بيري
Next up,
،تاليًا
{he has only been called an Emperor of the Sea for six years...-OG}he has only been called an emperor for six years...
...حصل على لقب اليونكو قبل ست سنواتٍ فحسب
He's the youngest of the four and deeply trusted by his subordinates...
إنّه الأصغر سنًّا من بينهم الأربعة ...ويتمتع بثقة عمياء من أعوانه
Beckman.
.بيكمان
Roux.
.رو
Yasopp.
.ياسوبّ
His top officers gained notoriety individually,
،اكتسب كبار قادته سمعة كلّ على حدّة
{and his undefeatable group has a high average bounty and the best balance of any groups...-OG}and with a high average bounty, his undefeated crew is the most well-rounded of them all.
ومجموعته الّتي لا تُهزم لديها معدّل مكافآت ...مرتفع وأفضل توازن بين أيّ مجموعة أخرى
The chief of the Red Hair Pirates...
...زعيم قراصنة الشّعر الأحمر
Red-Haired Shanks!
!شانكس ذو الشعر الأحمر
4,048,900,000 belly!
!أربعة مليارات و48 مليونًا و900 ألف بيري
Next...
،ونُكمل
{She's a natural-born monster who allegedly destroyed the village of Elbaf-OG}As a child, this natural-born monster laid waste...
إنّها وحش بالفطرة يُزعم أنّها دمّرت ...قرية إلباف عندما كانت طفلة
She only trusts her blood relatives
،لا تثق إلاّ في أقاربها وأبنائها الخمسة والثّمانين بنت هذه الملكة المستبدة أرض توتو
the queendom made of candy!
!مملكةُ مشيَّدةُ من الحلوى
The captain of the Big Mom Pirates!
!قبطانة قراصنة بيغ مام
Charlotte Linlin!
!شارلوت لينلين
4,388,000,000 belly!
!أربعة مليارات و388 مليون بيري
Lastly, during his time with the old Rocks Pirates,
.وبعدهما، كان عضوًا في قراصنة الروكس القدماء
he was just an apprentice pirate...
...كان مجرّد قرصان متدرّب
{But thereafter, he earned the respect of vicious pirates by his strength alone,-OG}But thereafter, he earned the respect of vicious pirates through strength alone,
ولكن بعد ذلك، حاز على احترام ،قراصنة متوحّشين بقوّته فحسب
{and ended up being called an Emperor of the Sea!-OG}and attained the title of emperor!
،وانتهى به المطاف بحمل لقب اليونكو
The viceroy of the Beast Pirates!
،القائد العامّ لقراصنة مملكة الوحوش
Kaido, King of the Beasts!
!ملك الوحوش كايدو
4,611,100,000 belly!
!أربعة مليارات و611 مليونًا و100 ألف بيري
I feel depressed...
...أشعر بالاكتئاب
By the decision at the Reverie,
،«حسبما قُرّر في مؤتمر «ليفيلي
{we can't deploy the Seven Warlords to fight these Four Emperors anymore!-OG}we can't deploy the Seven Warlords to fight the Four Emperors anymore!
ما عاد بإمكاننا إرسال !الشّيتشيبوكاي لقتال اليونكو بعد الآن
Whether removing that poison was correct or not...
...سواء كان تخلُّصنا من ذلك السّمّ صوابًا أم لا
{It's up to how well SSG, the Navy's Special Science Group, performs.-OG}is up to how well SSG, the Navy's Special Science Group, performs.
فالأمر منوط بمدى نجاعة مجموعة .«البحريّة العلميّة الخاصّة «م غ خ
For your reference,
،وكمرجعٍ لكم
here are the bounties of other legendary figures!
!إليكم مكافآت شخصيات أسطوريّة أخرى
The captain of the Whitebeard Pirates!
،قبطان قراصنة اللّحية البيضاء
Edward Newgate!
!إدوارد نيوغيت
5,046,000,000 belly!
!خمسة مليارات و46 مليون بيري
The captain of the Roger Pirates!
،قبطان قراصنة روجر
The King of the Pirates, Gold Roger!
،ملك القراصنة غولد روجر
5,564,800,000 belly!
!خمسة مليارات و564 مليونًا و800 ألف بيري
No pirates have ever surpassed these two...
...لم يستطع أيّ قرصان تجاوزهما
but once Kaido and Big Mom's alliance is formed,
،لكن بمجرّد تحالف كايدو وبيغ مام
{the sum of their bounties will surely top those numbers!-OG}the sum of their bounties will easily top those numbers!
فإنّ مجموع مكافآتهما سيتغلّب !على هذه الأرقام فعلًا
{But now in Wano which isn't affiliated with the government–-OG}Right now, in the unaffiliated Wano Country–
...لكن حاليًّا في بلاد وانو الّتي لا تتبع للحكومة
Fleet Admiral Sakazuki!
!أميرال الأسطول ساكازوكي
Forget about Wano!
!انسَ أمر بلاد وانو
We don't have any resources available to send on its behalf,
إننا نفتقر للموارد اللازمة !لتولّي أمرها يا سينغوكو-سان
Of course, I wasn't intending on getting involved...
...بالطّبع، لم أكن أنوي التّدخّل
{I was just conveying my knowledge as an old soldier to young soldiers.-OG}I was just providing these young marines with the knowledge of a veteran.
كنتُ فقط أشارك معرفتي مع الجنود .اليافعين بصفتي جنديّا قديمًا
Pirates share histories as well.
.حتّى القراصنة لديهم علاقات إنسانية
Those relationships influence their actions.
.لديهم أهداف لتحرّكاتهم
{You can't see what'll come next if you don't know history.-OG}We can't predict their movements if we ignore their pasts.
لا يمكنك رؤية المستقبل .إن كنتَ جاهلًا بالتاريخ
Oh, yeah...
...صحيح
There was a pirate from Wano who was favored by Whitebeard, Roger, and Red Hair.
كان هنالك قرصانٌ من بلاد وانو حاز على .إعجاب اللحية البيضاء وروجر وذو الشعر الأحمر
You mean Kozuki Oden?
أتعني كوزكي أودين؟
The man who once served as a commander on Whitebeard's ship...
الرجل الذي خدم في السابق .كقائد في سفينة اللحية البيضاء
{Oden was later headhunted by Roger and accompanied him on his last journey...-OG}Oden was later recruited by Roger and accompanied him on his final voyage.
...انضمّ أودين لاحقًا إلى روجر ورافقه في آخر رحلاته
{There's no way that Oden has something to do with what's happening...-OG}I can't imagine Oden has anything to do with this mess...
...من المستحيل أنّ لأودين علاقة بما يحدث الآن
{But why do those big-time pirates who disturb the world...-OG}but why do all these big-time pirates who disrupt the world...
لكن لماذا هؤلاء القراصنة الكبار ...الّذين يؤرقون العالم
always get involved with Wano?
يتورّطون دائمًا مع بلاد وانو؟
I think it's too much to be a coincidence...
...أجد أنّ الأمر أكبر من محض مصادفة
Sakazuki!
!يا ساكازوكي
Video Editing: Gigglebot Timing: Gab Typesetting: PhosCity Gab Quality Control: Feeso Galaxy 9000 Pepperjack Raiyan Scolines Zenef Soundtracking: Halee Graphics: Datenshi
Gigglebot PhosCity Gab FiberAhmed Feeso Galaxy 9000 Pepperjack Raiyan Scolines Zenef Halee Datenshi
Subtitle Editing: AphantasticRabbit Poppy Westfal Translation: arch1t3cht Funimation Gaijin PamkinPinguin rangicus
Crunchyroll